<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>disaster-recovery on @abiydv</title>
    <link>https://abiydv.github.io/topics/disaster-recovery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in disaster-recovery on @abiydv</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abiydv.github.io/topics/disaster-recovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS Backup</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/aws-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/aws-backup/</guid>
      <description>Questions What is lifecycle tiering? Transition backups from warm storage to cold storage. Only available for EFS, DynamoDB, Timestream database, VMWare VMs
Backup plan defines when and how to backup resources
Backup vault Encrypted storage location (per region) that stores the backups
Audit and report compliance of data protection policies Deploy central backup policies via AWS Organizations
cloud S3 EFS FSx EBS EC2 Windows VSS services on EC2 SAP HANA on EC2 DynamoDB RDS Aurora DB Cluster Neptune DB DocumentDB Redshift manual snapshot Timestream database Cloudformation stacks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Elastic Disaster Recovery Service (DRS)</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/drs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/drs/</guid>
      <description>Questions How does it compare with other AWS tools like VM import/export, Server Migration Service, AWS Migration Service (MGN) Unique property others don&amp;rsquo;t have - failover orchestration.
Elastic Disaster Recovery (DRS) The full name is Elastic Disaster Recovery. However, the short form is DRS (Disaster Recovery Service).
What does it do? Failover from on-prem to AWS Failover from any cloud to AWS Failover from 1 AWS region to another AWS region No need to maintain a duplicate recovery site Agent based - need to install an agent on source server to replicate data to AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
