<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>architecture on @abiydv</title>
    <link>https://abiydv.github.io/topics/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in architecture on @abiydv</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abiydv.github.io/topics/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS Well Architected</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/aws-well-architected/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/aws-well-architected/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Pillars 6 pillars of AWS Well Architected framework, as of 05-Dec-2023
S Security C Cost Optimization O Operational Excellence R Reliability P Performance Efficiency S Sustainability Patterns Static Stability https://aws.amazon.com/builders-library/static-stability-using-availability-zones/
Be ready for impairments before they happen
Over-provisioning is not necessarily a bad thing. It can provide some static stability in the sense that an AZ failure will not cause a full outage, the existing capacity in other AZ can continue to handle the load while the fault recovers or additional capacity is provisioned reactively to the AZ failure event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-AZ Architectures</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/multi-az-rchitectures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/multi-az-rchitectures/</guid>
      <description>Questions What is the scope? AZ, Regional, Global
When or why will you choose both CloudFront AND Load balancer?
What is an AZ? AZ or availability zone is an independent data center within a specific geographic region. An AWS Region is a collection of multiple availability zones. Regarded as a fault boundary. Data transfer across AZ is not free. Cross AZ traffic should be controlled for cost optimization and performance efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
