<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>containers on @abiydv</title>
    <link>https://abiydv.github.io/topics/containers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in containers on @abiydv</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abiydv.github.io/topics/containers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Containers</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/containers/</guid>
      <description>Introduction traditional runtime env is physical/virutal host
self contained, no dependency problems
portable, platform independent
OCI Open containers initiative ensures compatibility between containers created in different container engine env
Architecture build on top of linux kernel features
namespaces provide strict isolation at kernel level
cgroups provide resource allocation to ensure dedicated resources to containers
selinux helps enforce security, can also secure access to containers from the kernel
Container Images Built in multiple layers of filesystem</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/docker/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Dockerfile FROM =&amp;gt; a base image to use while building image ADD =&amp;gt; copy from local to container RUN =&amp;gt; execute commands to generate the image, this does not run when container starts CMD [&amp;#34;/usr/bin/nmap&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;-s&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;172.17.0.0/24&amp;#34;] =&amp;gt; default command to run at container startup, if not specified, container starts and stops immediately Docker cli docker build . -t myawesomeimage:v1 docker run myawesomeimage:v1 pull image myawesomeimage:v1, and run container docker run -d nginx run a container in background docker run -it ubuntu:latest /bin/bash open an interactive shell within the container ctrl-p, ctrl-q does not kill the container started with it flag docker inspect container_name json output of all properties of the container docker inspect &amp;lt;container id&amp;gt; --format=&#39;{{.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K8s Scheduling</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/k8s-scheduling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/k8s-scheduling/</guid>
      <description>Which pod goes where?
How does it help? Opportunities for cost saving by utilizing better scheduling. snorkel ai case-study Restrict workloads to specific nodes. Ex - run gpu workloads on gpu nodes, or don&amp;rsquo;t run cpu-only workloads on gpu nodes. Some users want to put multiple pods that communicate with one another in the same zone to avoid inter-zone traffic charges [[aws-well-architected#AZ Affinity]]
Anti-affinity is useful to spread pods across failure domains/topology (AZ or Region)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K8s Helm Charts</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/k8s-helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/k8s-helm/</guid>
      <description>Package manager for all the manifests that need to be deployed to a cluster
Components
chart.yaml - metadata about the chart values.yaml - values for variables exposed by the chart author templates dir - yaml manifest that define the rsources/objects to be deployed, variables are replaces with values as specified in values.yaml Search charts called database in default repository helm seach hub database
Add a custom repository helm add repo myrep https://myrepo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>K8s Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/k8s-main/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/k8s-main/</guid>
      <description>Architecture graph LR; c1(Cluster) --&gt; n1(node1) --&gt; p11[pod 1] n1 --&gt; p12[pod 2] c1 --&gt; n2(node2) --&gt; p21[pod 1] API docs - https://kubernetes.io/docs/reference/generated/kubernetes-api/v1.24/
Insert diagram about control nodes + worker nodes + api servers etc.
#refine https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/architecture/
Components Metric Server Use HostNetwork
Helps monitor pods Can run kubectl top pod to check resource usage for pods kubectl top nodes
CNCF Project status graph LR; a(Sandbox
New) --&gt; b(Incubating
More wide-spread adoption, active development) --&gt; c[Graduated</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
