<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>secrets on @abiydv</title>
    <link>https://abiydv.github.io/topics/secrets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in secrets on @abiydv</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abiydv.github.io/topics/secrets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cryptograpghy</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/cryptography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/cryptography/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Ciphers Algorithms, workflows Symmetric Asymmetric References As an outside-the-box approach, some organizations choose to encrypt sensitive data via code, processing the data while it is in the web servers and before transmitting it to the next tier. Access to the decryption keys is granted to specific application servers that handle decryption requests. This scheme can be extended further, to the user side, by encrypting the sensitive data field using a public key in the client-side code before transmitting it to the web server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Secrets Manager</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/secrets-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/secrets-manager/</guid>
      <description>Scope Region
Features Multi region - replicate easily Automatic key rotation, uses lambda Encrypted in-transit, at-rest Supports SecretString, SecretBinary. Within SecretString, it&amp;rsquo;s advisable to save data as json. Ref Alternatives SSM Parameter store</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Systems Manager (SSM)</title>
      <link>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/systems-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abiydv.github.io/notes/aws/systems-manager/</guid>
      <description>SSM Agent Most SSM functionality depends on this agent being present on the instance to be managed. Pre-installed on Amazon Linux Needs permission AmazonSSMManagedInstanceCore Use VPC endpoint Application Manager Logical grouping of resources to help provide context around resources, and while troubleshooting issues. Discovers related resources automatically, for ex, using CloudFormation templates.
AppConfig Store and manage configs for environment separate from app code.
Parameter Store No support for multi region No Rotation Optional encryption in-transit, at-rest Region scope Similar to Secrets Manager Change Management Change Manager Change Calendar: Decide, plan and enforce when changes, can or cannot be made to resources.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
